<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="previous_title">
        <item>Autonomous Electroplating Station</item>
        <item>Face Detection Based Electricity Control</item>
        <item>Basic Calculator on ATMEGA16</item>
		<item>Data Logging with Micro SD card</item>
		<item>Wireless Gesture Controlled Robot</item>
		<item>RF Energy Harvesting Based Battery less E-Paper</item>
		<item>Railway Signalling for Fog Mitigation / Poor Visibility</item>
		<item>Autonomous Buggy</item>
		<item>Web Monitor- Low Cost Video Surviellance Robot</item>
		<item>Ethernet and SMS Based Home Automation with Enhanced Security</item>
		<item>Low Cost ECG Signal Acquisition and Feature Extraction with Computer Aided Analysis</item>
		<item>STBCFG01 based Back Cover Battery Charger</item>
		<item>Autonomous Underwater Vehicle (Safina-e-Abdoz)</item>
		<item>Autonomous Reaction Vessel</item>
		<item>Stationary Device for Harvesting Energy from Railway Tracks</item>
		<item>GSM Based Result System</item>
		<item>Autonomous Athletic Time Keeping Device</item>
		<item>Laser Tag ShowDown</item>
		<item>IOT Based Home Appliances Controlled through Wireless Sensor Networks</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="previous_about">
        <item>The Electroplating Station has been designed keeping in mind the requirements of Rail-Trolley System. We have subsidized the cost of manufacturing by implementing the support system which is indeed capable of upholding chassis and rail-trolley system. 
	    The purpose of using the rails is the need for smooth movement of chassis carrying metal plate. The pulley so chosen that it is sufficiently strong to bear the load of metal piece to be electroplated. The supports are fixed at wooden base to provide tough structure to the whole station. All containers so chosen are fixed in separate compartments assigned to wooden base.
	    The motors so chosen that they sufficiently check the speed of chassis for its motion from 1 station to another. The motor used for driving blower are so chosen that they sufficiently wipe the extra droplets from metal piece. The motor used for Pulley is heavy as it directs the pulley to uphold the entire weight of metal piece. Also the wooden base is also sufficiently strong enough to bear the entire weight of all sub-stations. The fixed wooden base and rails also provides a means to carry the whole Electroplating Station at once, thus this whole arrangement is mobile from 1 place to another. </item>

        <item>The solution implements Face detection to detect a human presence and accordingly turn on/ off the supply of the place under consideration. Thus, the electricity supply is maintained when people are present (i.e. when need of electricity is there, for example in classrooms, conference rooms/halls, houses, etc.). The proposed concept could also be used for monitoring and surveillance purposes also. </item>

        <item>This was implementation of a hardware based calculating device for basic calculations. Main components used were used a ATMEGA16 microcontroller, a LCD screen and a 4x4 Key panel. </item>

        <item>Stand alone data loggers are compact, reusable and portable. Here we have used 2GB SanDisk Micro SD card to act as an external memory device to store environmental data. Micro SD card supports SPI and so it is interfaced with MicroController Atmega 32. The data is transferred between the memory card and the host controller as data blocks in unit of 512 bytes. data is stored using FAT32 library by elm-chan. Various sensors like temperature sensor (LM35) Pressure Sensor (MPX4115), height sensor (GP2D12) etc are interfaced to MCU using ADC port. To give data according to real time we have used Real Time Clock (RTC) DS1307 . It is interfaced with MCU using I2C protocol. Data received by sensors are directed to MCU where it is processed and directed to micro SD Card with real date and time. Data is stored in CSV format so that we can read the date in Microsoft Excel. </item>

        <item>Gesture recognition is a topic in computer science and language technology with the goal of interpreting human gestures via mathematical algorithms. Gestures can originate from any bodily motion or state but commonly originate from the face or hand. Gesture recognition can be seen as a way for computers to begin to understand human body language, thus building a richer bridge between machines and humans than primitive text user interfaces or even GUIs (graphical user interfaces), which still limit the majority of input to keyboard and mouse.
        Gesture recognition enables humans to communicate with the machine (HMI) and interact naturally without any mechanical devices.
        Here we are using a accelerometer in conjunction with a MCU and RF link to make a gesture controlled Robot. </item>

        <item>The present report deals with the detail description of the project "RF Energy harvesting based battery less E-Paper" that have been carried out during the internship at STMicroelectronics. An electrophoretic display is a type of low-power thin display that can retain its information for a very long period without power once it has been updated. E-Paper from company Pervasive Displays has been used throughout my project. This E-paper supports the SPI protocol in bidirectional mode which is used to interface it with ST’s microcontroller. A specific procedure according to the datasheet is followed to update the display. Three stages are required after which new image evoke on the display which can persist for long till next update. </item>

        <item>A basic problem we have often came across or heard of is due to fog or other unfavorable weather conditions when the visibility ceases to zero and hence the railway signal becomes less visible to the rail operator and leading to a chance of either an accident or delay in the rail schedule. Both these situations cannot be a part of a flourishing railway organization. The proposed logic revolves around Fog Signaling Using Radio Frequency .</item>

        <item>This project is a prototype to demonstrate the locomotion of autonomous urban passenger vehicles. It makes to and fro movement from one stop to the other via several other intermediate stops. This project can be further extended to implement other fuctions and safety features </item>

        <item>This robot is a low cost solution for remote video surveillance. Costing around INR 2,500 this robot transmits video into a remote computer operated through a Graphical Interface (GUI) running on the computer. The movement is manually controlled and uses parallel port communication. </item>

        <item>The most important feature of the home is that electrical appliances can be controlled from anywhere through a protected webpage. The automated home is well equipped with various sensors which are SMS controlled. The main entrance is password protected and employed with sms notification in case of any breach. Image Processing based Garage gate opening is also employed. Other remarkable features include Automatic Water Level indicator, LPG indicator, alarming and sms notification in case of security and safety breach etc. </item>

        <item>The present paper proposes a system design of Electrocardiogram (ECG) system to be used to acquire ECG signals and to enable a computer aided analysis of the same according to medical standards. The paper deals in detail the system design which is meant to provide a framework for developing useful embedded tools for easy, timely, cheap and accurate detection of heart abnormalities and cardiac murmurs which often go unnoticed in absence of trained physicians. The tagline of the system is its low cost that sets it apart from the peer in the market. A dedicated display unit for displaying the waveforms is bypassed, hence reducing the cost reasonably, instead the computer screen is used as the display unit of system, thus making it possible for further analysis and interpretation. LabVIEW is used for signal analysis, however dedicated software for the sole purpose can be developed in the future.  </item>

        <item>The system is based upon STBCFG01 IC which is a Switched mode single cell Li+ battery charger with OTG boost, voltage mode fuel gauge and LDO. The aim of the system is to make a low cost, robust and highly efficient backup extender for smartphones which will fit on the phone like a backcover. The back cover will have a battery of its own to provide the extended backup. A push switch is used to provide the control to the user for turning the system on and off and also for selecting between phone charging and backup battery charging. A LED based display section is integrated in the system to indicate the level of battery. </item>

        <item>In the present work, a Hybrid AUV named SEA 1.0 (Safina - E - Aabdoz), has been designed on simple hydrodynamic principles to achieve precise underwater movements so as to facilitate oceanographic observation. An indigenous control system is developed for this Underwater Vehicle moving in 3D space and having 4 controls, namely a suction mechanism for providing upward and downward movement (buoyancy control), thrusters to control forward motion respectively. Apart from this, a Robotic arm is also attached to pick and drop objects at specific location. </item>

        <item>The project involves the automation of reaction vessel. A Reaction Vessel is an essential component of Chemical Plant. All the processes taking place within the vessel are to be maintained. The control system is designed so as to achieve the recommended conditions required for chemical reaction to occur. The control system is designed as follows
 		i) If the temperature is low, heating and circulation should start.
 		ii) If the temperature is high, cooling and circulation should take place. 
 		iii) If the pressure is sensed low, heating and circulation should start and additionally the state should turn to startup. 
 		iv) If the pressure is high, an alarm is triggered which could be reversed by acknowledging the alarm button or by switching off the system. </item>

        <item>Harvesting energy from renewable sources has been in demand formany years. We have thought to go in different way by utilizing energy from moving train. A stationary device is placed on the railway track to harvest energy from the moving train by using ‘scotch yoke mechanism’. As we all know that world is in search of alternative form of energy, whether it is in the form of wind, solar, hydro etc. There is a lot of energy in the universe which is not utilized or wasted .There is a great need of harvesting this energy from various sources. As we all know that trains consume lot of energy in the form of electricity or coal for their propulsion but making energy from the train is a challenging task. This project deal with the harvesting of energy from moving train by putting stationary device on the track. Energy is stored in the battery by the moving the motor through the mechanism and that energy can be used for applications such as wireless tracking, signalling and health of monitoring tracks etc. </item>

        <item>The purpose of the design model is to access the result by the students via single SMS over their mobile phones. Project can be scalable to Offices where Employees can get their monthly report evaluation result or can be used to broadcast the urgent message to all the employees of a subdivision in the company.
 		The prototype model uses UART Protocol to interface GSM Modem and I2C Protocol to interface external EEPROM with Microcontroller. The purpose of GSM Modem is to send and receive the message from recipients whereas EEPROM stores the database of Result along with Individuals Student Id. Microcontroller acts as a link between GSM Modem and EEPROM and processes the data to deliver correct message to correct Individual. 
 		Prototype Design Model uses some standard components such as GSM Modem SIM300, AVR Microcontroller, USBASP AVR Programmer, EEPROM 24C512 IC, 7805 Voltage Regulator and few other miscellaneous components. </item>

 		<item></item>

        <item>The purpose of the project is to design a Wearable Sensor Technology based Electronic Jackets that can be used to sense the laser beams falling over them. The project aims to deliver a fun Event with a practical approach in Embedded Electronics. Electronic Jackets are given to students from different departments of University to use them in their own way.
 		The system design uses a sensor network over each Electronic Jacket, controlled by AVR Microcontrollers. The laser diode is used as a laser gun to locate their enemies.</item> 

		<item></item> 
		
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="previous_team">
        <item>Anand Agrawal, Udit Chauhan, Shivam K. Sundaram, Zainab Zaheer, Abu Talha Danish </item>

        <item>Faraz Ahmad, Firdaus Khan, Heena Mariyam</item>

        <item>Abu Talha Danish</item>

        <item>Ali Shazan, Aftab Usmani, Haris Siddiqui, Md. Rashid Azam</item>

        <item>Aftab Usmani, Haris Siddiqui, Ambreen Bano, Nishi Agrawal</item>

        <item>Md Haris Siddiqui</item>

        <item>Faraz Ahmad</item>

        <item>Faraz Ahmad</item>

        <item>Faraz Ahmad, Shahbaz Khan</item>

        <item>Aftab Usmani, Haris siddiqui, Ali Shahzan, Muhammad Asif</item>

        <item>Aftab Usmani, Haris siddiqui, Ali Shahzan</item>

        <item>Mohd. Aftab Usmani</item>

        <item>Ali Shahzan Gulrez, Mohd. Haris Siddiqui, Jatin Varshney, Abu Shahzer, Faraz Ahmad Khan</item>

        <item>Ali Shahzan Gulrez</item>

        <item>Haroon Rahman, Aftab Ansari</item>

        <item>Anand Agrawal</item>

        <item></item>

        <item>Anand Agrawal</item>

        <item>Anand Agrawal</item>



    </string-array>

    <string-array name="previous_images">
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/ELP/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/FaceDetection/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/BasicCalculator/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/DataLogging/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/GestureRobot/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/EPaper/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/FogMitigation/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/AutoBuggy/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/WebMonitor/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/HomeAutomation/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/LowCostECG/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/STBCFG/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/Safina/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/AutonomousReaction/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/img/robo.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/projects/GSMBasedResult/thumb.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/img/robo.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/img/robo.jpg</item>
        <item>http://www.amuroboclub.in/img/robo.jpg</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="current_title">
        <item>Application Development For Maintaining Database</item>
        <item>Automatic Vehicle Speed Control Wirelessly</item>
        <item>Developing A Server,Accessible Through Internet</item>
        <item>Development Of A Mobile Detector </item>
        <item>Drone Based Monitoring For University Campus\n(Sponsored by Sarfaraz Khan, Roboclub Alumni)</item>
        <item>Gesture And Voice Controlled Wheelchair</item>
        <item>GSM Based Vechile Tracking System</item>
        <item>IR Based Remote Control With Sensing Unit</item>
        <item>Two Link Robot Controller</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="current_team">

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="current_about">

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="current_images">

    </string-array>

</resources>
